<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[arstler]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[arstler]]></description>
        <link>http://arstler.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 14:02:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://arstler.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 14:01:47 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World Map]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>World Map</h1>,<p>linocut print in gold and burnt sienna with gold pigment dusted over</p>,<p>© Genu Berlo</p>,<p>http://berlo.net/world-map</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/08482b78-16c8-4eea-8428-e08468a026ed.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/9334c39b-07a4-4e8d-a809-52c7a246e3db.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/cda2d955-3295-4592-9f89-fa079e61e378.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/36b40773-4399-4f14-a1e4-6316e99e5abb.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/48b8dad6-c042-4cd3-ad6c-f4b3ddf760ef.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/286cbdb3-574f-48e1-943e-d6fc12e77a2a.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/520574d1-8e25-4383-a4b1-97579891b9b6.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/d133cf47-e08b-4e77-9eed-170c393bc6db.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/6a916c44-390b-41e8-8ea2-cfca76460494.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/26fcd95c-7d4c-42f0-8c7f-fe706aba97e6.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/055c36b6-931e-4176-b18e-5b45c957e94a.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/world-map/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0bec187b-0a53-4d05-98f0-7211725dc98b</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 14:01:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Razvan Anton]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/6c17c69a481598615f3f08623a6e62f9/noop.jpg?input=https%3A%2F%2Fstatic1.squarespace.com%2Fstatic%2F5417546ee4b046f29ec584a2%2F55796fbee4b06e95d293bd77%2F55796fc1e4b00bf1e6878de9%2F1459438643185%2FAnton%2BRazvan%252CBrain%2B%252Cwatercolor%2Band%2Bpencil%2Bon%2Bpaper%252C32x40cm.jpg"><h1>Razvan Anton</h1><p>Eastwards Prospectus</p></article>,<p>I work with drawing and memory. Drawing is for me the most direct path towards a possible image. Memory is not the subject but the medium and drawing is a conscious choice of a medium beyond mediums, a language that has the advantage of keeping a safe distance from the norms of the art world. It is a continuous and open research that eludes conclusion. It is a process that leaves a trace. It is the trace of a thinking process and the image is its proof. The speed at which I think and observe is also the speed at which I draw. The mark, the path and the image belong to this visible process of constructing meaning. It is an imprecise and uncertain route meant to change, consolidate or contradict our views. It is a landscape of shifting geography where historical, political and personal elements hover relentlessly while searching for a state of balance.</p>,<p>Lucrez cu desenul și memoria. Desenul este pentru mine cel mai direct traseu către imagine. Memoria nu este subiectul, ci mediul, iar desenul reprezintă o alegere conștientă a unui mediu dincolo de medii, un limbaj care reușește să țină la distanță normele lumii artistice. Este o cercetare continuă și deschisă care eludează concluziile. Desenul este un proces care lasă urme, urme ale procesului de gândire, iar imaginea este proba. Durata petrecută gândind și observând este și durata petrecută desenând. Urma, traseul și imaginea aparțin acestui proces vizibilal construcției sensului. Este o cale nesigură și imprecisă menită să schimbe, să consolideze sau să contrazică ceea ce cunoaștem. Este peisajul unei geografii schimbătoare unde elementele istorice, politice și personale orbitează fără întrerupere în căutarea unei stări de echilibru.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/razvan-anton/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a2f99003-daf6-4e15-8507-64d1ac91eb29</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 14:01:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Home]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Home</h1><p>For Creatives By Creatives</p><img src="http://static1.squarespace.com/static/577a359a2994caf1d48e19be/t/578ad176ebbd1a6a9102327d/1468715382918/Screen+Shot+2016-07-17+at+10.25.22+am.png?format=1000w"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.crookspress.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bfb0f8a3-5817-4d91-86de-ec6d590502ef</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 14:00:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WORDISIAC]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>WORDISIAC</h1><p>Frameable Vibes</p><img src="http://68.media.tumblr.com/avatar_ba182b78462e_128.png"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://wordisiac.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">dbb80e06-5853-449b-91c1-de914e06cda3</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 13:54:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[paci contemporary gallery / porto cervo, italy]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>paci contemporary gallery / porto cervo, italy</h1>,<p><em><strong>Ensconced in the northern coastal jet-setting playground of Porto Cervo, Sardinia, famous for its jeweled-toned sea, sits another gem portside_not to be overlooked.</strong></em></p>,<p>While the buoyant glitterati ready yachts and great sailing vessels for adventures in paradise_ toasting to the magnificence surrounding the Bai of Sardinia, and the curious gather for celebrity sightings along the The Costa Smeralda, the Promenade du Port aka The Costa Smeralda Hub_ lies several meters inland from the mighty seafaring crafts. Designed as a “luxury space where people can gather day or night”, it is complete with international art galleries, high-end retailers, bars and fine dining establishments, and an array of events_ all with first class offerings.</p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/49f07c81068668a20ece44566dda76f5810e2149.png">,<p>Paci Contemporary Gallery is among those glamorous offerings. Sitting pretty, shade side, the Paci Gallery sets its own course. Currently playing host to several photographic legends on both sides of the camera with an exhibition entitled “<em>Moda and Cinema”</em>, I was delighted to have the opportunity to view this collection of some of the most iconic women of the silver screen. The beauty was delivered_san aucun doute, not only detailing trends in fashion and makeup, but the posture, allure and enchantment of decades past, now preserved forever in archives, and brought back to life as the current vogue dictates. While the exhibition is well suited to it’s locale (Prince Aga Kahn’s creation) Paci’s presentation of the provocative and seductive is an engaging selection by the likes of such photographic luminaries as Douglas Kirkland, Bert Stern, William Klein, and Terry O’Neil, among others.</p>,<p>What is evident as you make your way around the gallery is how the photographers are aligned in the use of a “language”. To connect with their subject, the photographer must secure trust. The language is flirtation_ both visual and spoken, and very subtle, as it is the most important element in this photographic process. As an example, and most notably, Bert Stern has captured his star_ Marilyn, allowing the viewer to access the defining moment where intimacy is captured. And the result from Stern is clear in the outcome_ Monroe’s vulnerability. With vulnerability revealed, the intention is a success.</p>,<p>You can still catch the works, as they are on display until 30 September.</p>,<p>For additional information on upcoming exhibitions visit:<br><a href="mailto:info@pacicontemporarygallery.com">info@pacicontemporarygallery.com</a> / pacicontemporary.com<br>Promenade du Port_Via Aga Khan1 Porto Cervo, Italy</p>,<p>Image, courtesy of Paci Contemporary Gallery_Porto Cervo / 2017</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/paci-contemporary-gallery-porto-cervo-italy/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">443b23af-5a7e-44bd-ad5a-b728fe236810</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 19:32:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>