<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[arstler]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[arstler]]></description>
        <link>http://arstler.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 14:33:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://arstler.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 14:33:47 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[THE CHERKASHIN’S. NEW DRAWINGS. A NEW CHAPTER.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>THE CHERKASHIN’S. NEW DRAWINGS. A NEW CHAPTER.</h1>,<p>Renay Elle Morris / June 2017</p>,<p><strong>For decades, Valera and Natasha Cherkashin</strong> have added layer upon layer of philosophical and political ideology to their masterful works of photographic genius. With exhibitions, lectures and talks on an international stage, the art of their images have recently been compiled into a 254 page publication entitled, <strong>Actions, Happenings and art performances 1962 – 2016 _ Night with a Pioneer Leader</strong>, which delves into a history of 2 artists_a husband and wife team, and the legacy of their talent. What inspires them may not offer an easy answer. Perhaps it is a fearless energy to defend beliefs, or a lifetime of a Soviet regime. Perhaps it was Perestroika, the political movement and the "openness"policy that led to the reforms of the Soviet political and economic system during the1980s that allowed for such ambitious work.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/3df39e8c-e4a5-44a7-bc81-6191dc9c8271.jpg" title="&quot;Untitled 1&quot;">]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/the-cherkashins-new-drawings-a-new-chapter/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">61a19f96-b023-44ea-8447-9ea8f5af0929</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 14:33:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>© treasure of the heritage_st petersburg / renay elle morris /<a href="http://photopressimages.com/">photopressimages.com</a>/ 2017</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/b8732f4b-78a4-4017-a9a9-f5811c353043.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/c-treasure-of-the-heritage_st-petersburg-renay-elle-morris/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e6412b47-6e5c-4b58-96a2-215b72eef2a6</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 14:33:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Giuliana Lazzerini]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Giuliana Lazzerini</h1>,<p>Giuliana was born in Seravezza near Pietrasanta, Tuscany. Between 1962 and 1968 she was a student at the Istituto D’Arte Stagio Stagi in Pietrasanta, gaining a Master of Arts Diploma.This was followed by a further four years studying painting at the Accademia di Belle Arti in Carrara. She moved to Yorkshire in 1987 and now lives in York. The Tuscan landscape and childhood memories still bear a strong influence upon the artist’s current work. In an earlier statement she describes her first encounters with Art in Italy as a child in her father’s mosaic studio. She refers to the “translucency of the mosaic fragment” and her “fascination with the vibrancy of colour” from the juxtaposition of pieces. Her current works show an economy in terms of compositional design, with richness of surface mark and colour, reconfirming the artist’s earlier delight in light and transparency.</p>,<p><a href="http://www.giulianalazzerini.com/" title="">www.giulianalazzerini.com</a></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/9ebc3b3a-af5a-46b6-a2de-8d9c35d8c477.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/45134e66-0a1b-484b-97ae-d47bd69b155b.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/543472f2-c81f-4677-a899-8393a5deee74.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/a07cbaf4-b78e-4a6d-aba0-744f893e8684.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2b5e1347-820a-4384-97b5-a09d51281362.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/5b0beb06-dd1d-4093-b841-575fc427e424.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2ec1f6b2-9e57-498a-9d23-9a448250a9de.jpg">,<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/7c974150fce304afd5492549cb014b66/croprotate.jpg?cropheight=779&cropwidth=505&degrees=0&input=https%3A%2F%2Fthe-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2F785de4ea-55d3-4b95-b92a-7ad492fdb8b8.jpg&x=24&y=0">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/75c74999-f7a3-4267-8347-bcb04afb39f7.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/8e899e47-878a-4432-a19b-05b63d861683.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/6a29ed24-f967-45b1-9766-fb4adf66c850.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/71703b4b-e14b-4fea-b8d1-42a2a10d6d74.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/giuliana-lazzerini/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ba90e4a3-e940-456f-b258-1255c2da6b90</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 14:33:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[paci contemporary gallery / porto cervo, italy]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>paci contemporary gallery / porto cervo, italy</h1>,<p><em><strong>Ensconced in the northern coastal jet-setting playground of Porto Cervo, Sardinia, famous for its jeweled-toned sea, sits another gem portside_not to be overlooked.</strong></em></p>,<p>While the buoyant glitterati ready yachts and great sailing vessels for adventures in paradise_ toasting to the magnificence surrounding the Bai of Sardinia, and the curious gather for celebrity sightings along the The Costa Smeralda, the Promenade du Port aka The Costa Smeralda Hub_ lies several meters inland from the mighty seafaring crafts. Designed as a “luxury space where people can gather day or night”, it is complete with international art galleries, high-end retailers, bars and fine dining establishments, and an array of events_ all with first class offerings.</p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/49f07c81068668a20ece44566dda76f5810e2149.png">,<p>Paci Contemporary Gallery is among those glamorous offerings. Sitting pretty, shade side, the Paci Gallery sets its own course. Currently playing host to several photographic legends on both sides of the camera with an exhibition entitled “<em>Moda and Cinema”</em>, I was delighted to have the opportunity to view this collection of some of the most iconic women of the silver screen. The beauty was delivered_san aucun doute, not only detailing trends in fashion and makeup, but the posture, allure and enchantment of decades past, now preserved forever in archives, and brought back to life as the current vogue dictates. While the exhibition is well suited to it’s locale (Prince Aga Kahn’s creation) Paci’s presentation of the provocative and seductive is an engaging selection by the likes of such photographic luminaries as Douglas Kirkland, Bert Stern, William Klein, and Terry O’Neil, among others.</p>,<p>What is evident as you make your way around the gallery is how the photographers are aligned in the use of a “language”. To connect with their subject, the photographer must secure trust. The language is flirtation_ both visual and spoken, and very subtle, as it is the most important element in this photographic process. As an example, and most notably, Bert Stern has captured his star_ Marilyn, allowing the viewer to access the defining moment where intimacy is captured. And the result from Stern is clear in the outcome_ Monroe’s vulnerability. With vulnerability revealed, the intention is a success.</p>,<p>You can still catch the works, as they are on display until 30 September.</p>,<p>For additional information on upcoming exhibitions visit:<br><a href="mailto:info@pacicontemporarygallery.com">info@pacicontemporarygallery.com</a> / pacicontemporary.com<br>Promenade du Port_Via Aga Khan1 Porto Cervo, Italy</p>,<p>Image, courtesy of Paci Contemporary Gallery_Porto Cervo / 2017</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/paci-contemporary-gallery-porto-cervo-italy/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">443b23af-5a7e-44bd-ad5a-b728fe236810</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 19:32:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>