<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[arstler]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[arstler]]></description>
        <link>http://arstler.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 17:55:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://arstler.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 17:55:10 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Andrei Cădere ]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Andrei Cădere </h1>,<p><strong>André Cadere</strong> was born in Poland, grew up in Romania and died in Paris in 1978. He was best known for his handmade series of painted round wooden bars, challenging the boundaries between painting and sculpture. Cadere was one of the first artists to realize that objects were inseparable from market and institutional contexts: half of his focus was on the systems of distribution in the art world, as he introduced bars in galleries and retract them, usually carrying a bar like a staff. His bars could be positioned in all sorts of relations to their surroundings (on walls, floors, propped between the two, etc.), but he would also carry them around a number of outdoor locations and into other people’s shows and openings, even when not invited, which made him quite ”infamous” at the time. (He was nicknamed ”The Stick Man”.)</p>,<p><strong>Andrei Cădere </strong>(1934-1978) este unul dintre cei mai importanţi reprezentanţi ai artei conceptuale mondiale. Ca fiu al unui proeminent diplomat român, Andrei Cădere a suferit în primele decenii comuniste o existență marginală, sub supravegherea Securității. A emigrat în Franța în 1967 și, după mai mulți ani de căutări, a devenit o figură memorabilă a scenei culturale pariziene și nu numai. Mereu însoțit de faimoasele lui toiege sculptate și pictate, descinzând inopinat în cele mai neșteptate locuri, Cădere s-a impus drept unul dintre cei mai originali artiști conceptuali și performativi din arta contemporană, fiind în prezent artistul român cu cea mai mare circulație, pe plan mondial, după Brâncuși.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/44264f42-dfd9-4c72-bb60-605b578257a2.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/583d25f3-639c-42a4-bf48-549d4c7b5fe5.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/5a019dd8-2e7d-4615-a95d-224520852e30.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/57174502-4901-4b4d-a4c8-b4248cae88a0.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/a164c8c1-fce0-4120-8f7b-b6e47808b164.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f75dca66-e1df-4428-af79-44ea724affea.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/b5f4c44a-406d-498e-89b7-50d343e61af4.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2294662c-a776-4c42-9964-f66a469dabb7.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/c330119c-58e6-4c17-8c0c-7bfdc2eee25a.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2c03110e-39de-4c19-9c32-ffe5ec980038.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/dc50c97a-0e04-47dc-8a88-70897a3a5b7e.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/93154efa-a40c-4f64-a42d-f0fdee369fcb.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/33e8b969-5bff-41fe-8a50-a2627a8700b9.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/bdb56682-d5dd-44b2-9587-cde96d6b543f.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/03fa61ff-91d7-4699-a2b3-2f6f70f13576.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/8d5c8619-fea1-4ab9-ba40-36a1f4b52bf9.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/andrei-cadere/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">dcb91804-92b9-410b-a0cc-987729fdc140</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 12:24:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highlights of the 2017-18 Mdina Cathedral Art Biennale]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Highlights of the 2017-18 Mdina Cathedral Art Biennale</h1>,<p>BY RENAY ELLE MORRIS</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/808b2a3b-be1d-4e29-af25-cfa58a729758.png">,<p>© renay elle morris_ mdina, malta 2017</p>,<p><strong>In the afterglow of the visual conversation “The Mediterranean: A Sea of Conflicting Spiritualities”_ </strong>the 2017-18 APS <em>Mdina</em> Cathedral Contemporary Art <em>Biennale</em> held in the country of Malta, I am delighted to showcase a selection of interpretive works authored by an international network of artists and curated by a talented team, guided by artistic director Dr.Giuseppe Schembri-Bonaci and Nikki Petroni. It was a global triumph_ a narrative explored with diverse translations, creating a visual display in various mediums_ painting, sculpture, photography, and multimedia platforms_ artistic voices heard through the most personal of presentations.</p>,<p>In this 2nd edition, at the impressive the Mdina Cathedral Museum, over 30 works were presented throughout the treasury. The interplay of the works, installed on different landings, led the viewer on a spiritual traverse_ and to the cavernous underground passageway leveled below_ an ethereal space in itself.</p>,<p>With an invitation to participate, I delight in the bonds of friendship that were made through this distinctive and highly creative opportunity. Thus, I am proud to share this journey, and thank all the wonderful artists, academics, clergy and business entities, as well as visitors that have made this not only an exhibition, but a forum for its timely theme of conflicting spiritualities, an important one.</p>,<p><strong>The Artists_ The Works</strong></p>,<p><strong>Savina Capecci</strong> (in art Savina Kapecci)_ lives in Pordenone Italy, and studied at the Academy of Fine Arts in Venice where she received her B.A. in Painting in 2014 and her Master Degree in 2016 with full marks. She worked as assistant to the professors in the classes of painting at the Free Academy of Fine Arts in Klagenfurt, Austria as well as participating in selected exhibitions.</p>,<p>Capecci has received several art awards with her work included in a variety of publications.</p>,<ul><li>Premio Arte Cairo Mondadori Finalists exhibition, Palazzo Reale and Palazzo della Permanente, Milan</li><li>Transgenic Attack, Atelier der Stadt Klagenfurt, Austria solo exhibition</li><li>BV Sommerausstellung, BV Galerie, Klagenfurt, Austria</li><li>Memento Andy, Atelier 3+10, Venice</li><li>Fuori Uso, Avviso di garanzia, Ex Tribunal, Pescara</li><li>Premio Lilian Caraian, Museum of Modern Art Revoltella, Trieste</li><li>Incident III – Accident Czestochowa Museum, Poland</li></ul>,<p>The works presented at the Mdina Biennale are titled “The PromiSSed land”. The painted images depict the human aspect of the current immigration crisis happening in the Mediterranean sea, and are expressive of the essence of the concept of “waiting” in all its forms and feelings that arise while sitting in a boat. The Promised land inevitably becomes a “pro-missed” land.</p>,<p><a href="http://www.savinakapecci.com/">www.savinakapecci.com</a> / <a href="http://savina_capecci@libero.it/savinakapecci@gmail.com">savina_capecci@libero.it</a> / <a href="http://savina_capecci@libero.it/savinakapecci@gmail.com">savinakapecci@gmail.co</a>m</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/6eec7083-3d2d-4804-9412-79847f6754e8.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_ <strong>The PromiSSed land</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>James Alec Hardy_ </strong>born – 1979 in Colchester, England. The essence of James Alec Hardy’s practice is a process concerned with the impact of technologies on our experience of life. Since 2002, he has focused on analogue video systems, manifesting ideas through performance, sculpture, installation and print. By using obsolete devices from a former analogue age to reproduce digital functions, Hardy’s practice is challenging and engaging_ranging from building sculptural totems of video monitors, to 3 month long shamanic residencies in fields with I-Cabin, to 3 day long noise and feedback performances at The Tate Modern.</p>,<p>“With the truth being understood as subjective, the video sculptures I create do not limit freedom of thought, but stimulate choice. I aim to avoid manipulating the viewer by presenting ‘video as truth’, my work allows the video to function ultimately as the meditative stage for the mind, which unravels its own truth.”</p>,<p>1999-2002: Camberwell College of Arts, London<br>Present: Warrior Studios, London Represented by Kristin Hjellegjerde Gallery London</p>,<p>instagram @jamesalechardy / <a href="http://www.sitbackandrelapse.com/">www.sitbackandrelapse.com</a></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/c44906c9-5b83-4891-8986-69dd21bbaca9.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_<strong>“171111”</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Robert Stokowy_ </strong>is a sound artist, composer and artistic researcher from Cologne, Germany. His work entails experimental compositions, text based interventions, audiovisual performances and installations. All projects are framed by an overarching artistic research process, focussing on topics of instability, sensory balance, as well as qualitative characteristics and potentiality of sound and place. Stokowy’s site-specific Sound Installations are based on phenomenological practices and consist of small sounds which hold very haptic and organic qualities. With his works the artist wants to explore the potentiality of his sonic surroundings and give recipients access to experience new perspectives on their environment.</p>,<p>Since Stokowy’s work is first and foremost based on sound, a recording of the installation is available on his website.</p>,<p>Instagram: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/robertstokowy/">robertstokowy</a> / www.robert-stokowy.de</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/d9046899-eeb7-4fdd-a7b2-5b0ea6bd84c1.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_ <strong>structures [mdina]</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Anthony Catania_</strong> is a visual artist specializing in myths and fables. Often on the threshold of grotesque figurative painting, his style attempts to capture subversively idiosyncratic portraits of legendary beings embedded in bizarrely anachronistic settings. His personal exhibitions; <em>Selve Oscure</em>, <em>The Cave of Centaurs</em>, <em>The Piper’s Requiem</em>, <em>Spectre-Bark</em> and <em>Last Light</em>, were held at the Malta Museum of Fine Arts, the Malta Maritime Museum and Heritage Malta. Catania is a PhD candidate at the University of Malta, where he also received his MFA in Digital Arts with a distinction. Catania also worked as a concept designer for indie games<em>, </em>poster designer for theatre productions and illustrator of academic book covers. He currently lectures on illustration, primitivism and sequential art at the University of Malta.</p>,<p><em>Wilting Annunciation</em> depicts the typical scene where the angel Gabriel announces the birth of Christ and incarnation of God. The announcement is that of Christ’s passion endured for humanity’s redemption from the agony in the garden of Gethsemane until His death on Calvary. It also depicts the passion of a Mater Dolorosa who will cradle the corpse of her son through fertile/dead sunflower seeds. Death and life are depicted in an oxymoronic manner.</p>,<p>www.anthonycatania.com</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/3729e946-5f23-4a31-8d71-b3a08cb76f74.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_ <strong>Wilting Annunciation</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Gor Chahal_ </strong>was born in Moscow in 1961 and is one of the most highly accomplished contemporary artists. His creative method synthesizes a scholastic approach with the elements of a ritual. Chahal is of a type rarely found in the Russian artistic community: a «universal master», with a diploma in science and applied mathematics, from the Moscow Engineering and Physics Institute, a contributor to numerous creative experiments undertaken in cooperation with groups of poets, musicians, and artists of Soviet-era Underground. But while the style of Chahal’s creations lie within the parameters of Actual Art, yet in substance they are at the other end of the spectrum. His themes often encompass faith and show a deep awareness that true art simply cannot exist without connection to tradition of the sacred, Christianity in this case.</p>,<p>mail@chahal.ru</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2db1a211-836f-4df9-92ae-0d9b8fb23bd6.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_<strong>St. George strikes Cy Twombly, 2017</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Michael von Cube_ </strong>Born – 1952, Cube lives and works in Munich, Lower-Bavaria and Malta.</p>,<p>The reality of the political situation in the Mediterranean surpasses the image of brutality by far, and so the picture remains what it should be and is – a helpless plea: art.</p>,<p>When Johann Wolfgang von Goethe set off on his travels to Italy, the Age of Enlightenment was of great significance in Europe. The education system and lifestyle of the ancient world was seen as the model for a civil society. Committed to ‚Goodness, Truth and Beauty‘ (Winckelmann), artists and romantics from all walks of like were drawn to the cradle of European culture: The Mediterranean. The painter Johann Heinrich Wilhelm Tischbein created the famous portrait of the German writer entitled „Goethe in the Roman Campagna“.</p>,<p>‘Europium‘ takes an ironic look at this idealistic approach or what is indeed left of it today: The princess of peace and her system of values surrounded by lemons symbolising a united Europe. It refers to the vision of the writer, Goethe, just like peace-game‘ does to the abolition of violence and war.</p>,<p>www.michael-von-cube.de</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/b58a36d7-d793-4b49-af8f-90168fd46e9e.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_<strong>Europium</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Guy Ferrer_ </strong>is French, of Catalan and Italian descent. Over the past thirty years he has developed an international reputation as a painter and sculptor, with exhibitions in museums and galleries around the world. In addition to painting and sculpture his work also encompasses writing and architecture. Ferrer has worked in Paris, Los Angeles and other international cities, including New York, Caracas, Lima, Beijing and Johannesburg where he has created temporary studios. In 2012, the establishment of his studio in French Catalonia marked his return to the Mediterranean.</p>,<p>Recent honours include a monumental bronze sculpture for the French embassy in Singapore and a large fresco for the French embassy in Bakou (Azerbaijan). The OECD commissioned and permanently displays a large triptych by Ferrer entitled <em>Liberté-Egalité-Fraternité</em>.</p>,<p>“T.O.L.E.R.A.N.C.E”, a major sculptural work created in 2007 in response to contemporary religious tensions, has been widely acclaimed and displayed in France, Germany, Poland and the United Arab Emirates.</p>,<p>Ferrer’s work is represented in private and corporate collections around the world. He has developed artistic partnerships with several companies including <em>Lefranc &amp; Bourgeois, Champagne Jacquart</em> and <em>Le Bon Marché</em> in Paris where Ferrer’s monumental bronze, <em>La Pourvoyeuse,</em> is a permanent installation.</p>,<p>Atelier Guy Ferrer – France <a href="http://www.guyferrer.com/">guyferrer.com</a> / <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Guy-Ferrer-302275579973953/timeline/">Facebook</a></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/1336b941-4a99-46e9-ae66-01f06734d783.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_ <strong>Les Vigilants, 2007</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Zita Vilutyte_</strong> (Lithuania) is a painter, musician, and composer, as well as founder and artistic director of the Holistic Theatre of Movement “S”. In addition, she is a neuropsychoeducator, lecturer, curator and journalist. From 2013-2016, Vilutyte was Director of the International Art project ANIMA MUNDI, and as of 2016, President of the association.</p>,<p>Her career includes over 40 personal exhibitions as well as joint creative projects in various countries, including Lithuania, Latvia, Estonia, India, Italy, Denmark, Holland, Croatia, Germany, Georgia, England and Macedonia. In 2011 she received a bronze award in Art from the Five Golden Stars Gallery, Netherlands.</p>,<p>Other activities and participations, include:</p>,<ul><li>The release of 17 solo music albums</li><li>Music Composition for film and theatre</li><li>Musical and visual projects in coordination with the music group “VARTAI”</li><li>The production of 4 music CD’s in a joint musical project with Lithuanian musicians</li><li>Membership in the Ambient Music Association’s “Ambient Music Garden” (U.K.)</li></ul>,<p>www.iaf-animamundi.com</p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/438f90be206d95694b64afc4aa60f33b699083f1.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_ <strong>Exist, No Exit</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Ana Caterina Pereira_</strong> believes that materials determine the way humanity operates and her work is centred on their composition and behaviour. She is also interested on the impact their existence have in our society, in particular architecture, politics and gender roles. Steel is Pereira’s material of choice – its chemical properties and reactions determine the subject of the work. She combines this metal with other materials in order to activate or counteract their intrinsic properties.</p>,<p>Pereira completed her Masters at Chelsea College of Arts in 2012, being awarded with Clifford Chance Prize the following year. In 2014, Pereira received the Royal British Society of Sculptors Bursary. The work shown at Mdina Biennal in 2015 represents the beginning of a new body of work that explored the rigidity that characterises steel.</p>,<p>Pereira’s work was selected for several listings and shown in a variety of occasions, including the Aesthetic Art Prize (2014), Signature Art Prize (2015), Anthology (2016) and First@108 (2017). This last experience opened her the desire to work outdoors, which was realised with “Now outside the doors of strange houses”. Based on the study of steel’s atomic structure, this sculpture is on show at Broomhill Sculpture Park till May 2018.</p>,<p>anapereira@mail.com / <a href="http://www.anacatarinapereira.com/">www.anacatarinapereira.com</a></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/c763f390-4ec3-4c2e-bcdf-e456e78f0139.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_<strong>“not afraid of hot summer, nor of the frozen winter”</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Genia Chef_ </strong>was born in Kazakstan, in the former Soviet Union where his father, a photographer, had been banished during Stalin’s regime. Chef grew up in Moscow and studied graphic arts at the Polygraphic Institute receiving a Master of Fine Arts degree. He was awarded with the First Prize for his diploma (1977). After relocating to West Germany in 1985, he studied painting at the Vienna Academy of Fine Arts and was honoured with the Fueger Gold Prize (1993). He resides in Berlin.</p>,<p>Genia Chef is an author of theoretical works, including his “Manifesto of Post-Historicism”, and “Viva Canova”. Chef has participated in numerous museum exhibitions worldwide, including the F. Weisman Art Museum, Minnesota, Museum of Modern Art, Ostende, Belgium, Kunsthalle Baden-Baden, Germany, Palazzo Forti, Verona, Italy, State Russian Museum, Saint Petersburg, Yeshiva Univ. Museum, New York, Experimental Art Foundation, Adelaide, Australia, II Moscow Biennale, CUA Museum of the University of Colorado, Boulder, University of New Mexico Art Museum, Albuquerque, 55th and 56th Venice Biennale, Mdina Cathedral Biennale, Malta.</p>,<p>geniachef@gmx.de / <a href="http://www.geniachef.de/">www.geniachef.de</a></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/5b3d9210-12a9-49e6-99fd-e3e3d388a87c.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_ <strong>Red Square</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Lena Lapschina_ </strong>graduated from State Stroganow University of Fine and Applied Arts in Moscow. She lives and works in Vienna and Lower Austria. Lapschina has won the Austrian State Grant for Video and Media Art and was awarded several prestigious residencies, including the Djerassi Residence Artists Program (Woodside, California), KuS (Heerlen, Netherlands), ORTung (Strobl, Austria), and Nordens Hus (Reykjavík, Iceland).</p>,<p>In Lapschina’s three-channel video installation “Runtime”, a character is moving with great haste. It does so for minutes, for hours, for days. There’s no aim in sight, not even a fata morgana. Synchronously a timepiece slowly but surely is wandering across the scene. While at first glance the character seems to be driven by customary stress and inner conflicts, it turns out that the piece is tackling the more sensitive issues of modern societies. If the attire of the character is any indication, it’s about civilization at large, which in the eyes of many people is at stake these days. Maybe the artist wants to remind us of two facts: 1. People on this planet have been running along the surface of the earth’s crust in search for paradise for ages. 2. It’s the Mediterranean, which once again is the arena of the world’s greatest conflicts.</p>,<p><a href="http://www.lapschina.com/">www.LAPSCHINA.com</a></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/d2d1243d-5de5-4af8-8d1e-8f05ef3fd653.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_ <strong>Runtime</strong> / site-specific three-channel video installation with sound; dimensions variable. 2017</p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Aleko Lomadze_ </strong>is a Georgian artist whose work is iconographic in nature. His icons are housed in different temples in Georgia – Tbilisi, Ozurgeti, Choxatauri, and Xobi, as well as Vienna, Austria in the Holy Mother Temple. For nearly 15 years he has worked and noted for his work with draw milled stones, which is quite a time-consuming process. He collects the stones from all parts of Georgia with the assistance of associates. In addition to other mediums, he uses marble rug_ known for its radiance, and its use in painting.</p>,<p>Lomadze participates in different art projects, exhibitions, festivals, art seminars and workshops in Georgia and other countries including Lithuania, Latvia and Portugal. Many of his works are in private collections and public institutions throughout Georgia and abroad. With the blessing of the Georgian Patriarchate several works are kept in the Patriarchate.</p>,<p>In 2015 he joined the ANIMA MUNDI project.</p>,<p>www.iaf-animamundi.com</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/1c671f6c-9447-4c97-939b-83c353e3ae60.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_ <strong>Abstract 2</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Nicola Arkell Reed_ </strong>is an artist and lecturer, with a BA and MA in Fine Art from Central St. Martins. Reed exhibited in the Cathedral Crypt at the Mdina Biennale in 2016 and prior to that had a solo show at the Rebecca Hossack Gallery, Mayfair, London. She won National Geographic Magazine’s photography competition and was published in their October 2016 issue. In addition, she has illustrated two published novels: Fox by Anthony Gardner and Tittle Tattle by Bill Keeling and has tutored Fine Art at Chelsea College of Art and the University of Gloucestershire as well as run drawing workshops at the University of Malta, Chelsea College of Art and The Idler Magazine.</p>,<p>Nicola Reed uses the medium of photography, film and printmaking in her work. For many years, and as a mother of six children, her work was focused on, and explored Mother Daughter Dynamics, using herself and her three daughters as the subjects for a body of work. As a supporter of the charity EthiopiAid, and visiting and photographing the people of Ethiopia since the late 1980s, Reed produced a series of photographic portraits focused on the dissipating tribes and cultures in Ethiopia with the intention to celebrate the individuality, unique style and personality that is so pertinent to the people of the Omo Valley in Southern Ethiopia. Her current project is inspired by her passion for bee-keeping and protecting bees from the current and serious threat to their existence. More examples of Nicola’s work can be found on her website.</p>,<p><a href="http://www.nicolaarkell.com/">www.nicolaarkell.com</a></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/cfc85f95-4d37-4044-bcf2-248df9cff50e.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_<strong>The in between</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Merna Liddawi_ </strong>is an award winning British-Jordanian artist living in the UK. She is on a mission to capture the beauty of spiritual moments in our lives and deepen our connection with the Divine. Her unique technique of using traditional methods handed down from artisans, which she developed over many years, has caught the attention of art collectors, curators and art historians. Others have spoken of her work as “having an unexpected calming effect”.</p>,<p>After completing a science degree in Cairo, Liddawi moved to the UK where she taught Math for many years. She gained a BA in Fine Art and was awarded an MFA with distinction from West Dean College.</p>,<p>Liddawi’s work has been shown in several group exhibitions in London and had her solo show ‘Revelation’ at Asia House. She has exhibited internationally _ Venice and Portugal, and been selected for the Florence Biennale, Mdina Biennale in Malta as well as Artrooms London and Rome. She won the 2ndArtGemini Prize in Painting and Sculpture, and has been awarded the “Lorenzo il Magnifico” painting award in Florence. Liddawi is featured in several publications and has been nominated for the Edward James Foundation trustees award. Her paintings are housed in private collections in the Middle East, Europe, the USA and UK.</p>,<p><a href="http://www.mernaliddawi.com/">www.mernaliddawi.com</a> / <a href="mailto:info@mernaliddawi.com">info@mernaliddawi.com</a></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/32c0df56-34e0-4bac-a944-1271bb473e20.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_ <strong>Uncreated Light</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Aina Putnina_ </strong>born – 1962, graduated from the Art Academy of Latvia in 1992, and the Baltic International Academy in 2011 in Riga, Latvia. Since 1994 Putnina has participated in exhibitions, workshops, plain airs and other projects in Latvia, Lithuania, Belarus, and Georgia. Putnina has been employed at the Art School for children and adults teaching painting and computer graphics since 1993.</p>,<p>Putnina’s creative interest are painting and digital graphic media, and uses expressive abstract and landscape elements, as well as ornaments for the emotional narrative of composition while combines traditional painting with technology applications and is noted for her expressive use of color and tonal contrasts. Her works are characterized as emotionally expressive_telling stories with the use of colors, lines and shapes. Putnina notes that the simple geometric shapes and forms are messages from long time ago, and they are the witnesses of our creation and abstract thinking processes. Her work is an interpretation of nature_ forms around us and are an expression everyday life.</p>,<p>www.iaf-animamundi.com</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/519efed8-443d-41a9-82d2-5d4a291edf93.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_ <strong>River and Rain</strong></p>,<p>+</p>,<p><strong>Renay Elle Morris_</strong>a career in brief.</p>,<p>(USA – BFA_Graphic Design / Photography) Renay E. Morris is an internationally recognized writer, award-winning graphic designer and photographer. Pursing her education, she received her degree from the prestigious Krannert School of Art &amp; Design at the University of Illinois, with further studies at New York University and the Parsons School of Design. Throughout her career as a creative director, she incorporates the use of design and photography for the development of media programs for private and public organizations which have included; Universal Pictures, Sony Music/CBS Records, CBS Publications, and TDS Time Warner. With Corporate<strong>ID</strong>easWorldwide, and renayellemorris.com, she maintains a platform for visual communications for a global clientele.</p>,<p>As a journalist and member of the US and overseas press community, Morris was the international news editor for <em>Picture</em>magazine_a nominee for the coveted “Lucie” award. In addition to various publications, and as of 2016, she is the editor_ photographic &amp; fine art development/content of the online artist resource/gallery_ arstler.com.</p>,<p>Currently, her primary direction is fine art photography presented in large-scale format. Morris participates in gallery exhibitions in the United States and abroad with representation. She resides in Manhattan, New York.</p>,<p>renayelle@gmail.com</p>,<p><a href="mailto:rem@renayellemorris.com">rem@renayellemorris.com</a> / www.renayellemorris.com</p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/610a83b1c7cf57c85c732da1979ed92fc53f83b2.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_<strong>Lo Smarrito / The Lost</strong><br>+</p>,<p><strong>Maria Kaleta_&nbsp;</strong>as an artist, one always searches for meaning and morals that can be conveyed in their creations.&nbsp;For Maria, these lessons range from a whole host of different topics. She explores, for example, how, in an ever increasingly technological world, we can often lose sight of our identities. In turn, we observe how everything seems to revolve around the media and the trials of character that come with this, us now having to learn the difference between what can be useful and what can be dangerous, whether our sources of information can be trusted.</p>,<p>Having lived in London for well over a decade, Maria is also able to use this cultural hub as a rich source of inspiration for many of her works. Transposing the communities she observes there onto canvas or computer, Maria journeys through what it means to live in a multicultural society and all the highs and lows that come with it, living surrounded by vibrant peoples from a variety of origins.</p>,<p>With this in mind, she continues to investigate how persons can be drowned out by the sound of the city, what it means to lose your voice in the crowd and the effects this can have on your self.</p>,<p>With years of experience already behind her, the necessity for a togetherness between peoples seems a clear solution to some of such problems that Maria raises in her work. Art, however, cannot only be interpreted in one way or be deemed understood with but one solution. Instead, Maria's work allows for many morals and meanings to be open for the onlooker, with significance for many years to come.</p>,<p><a href="http://www.mariakaleta.com/">www.mariakaleta.com</a>&nbsp;/<a href="mailto:mariakaleta@gmail.com">mariakaleta@gmail.com</a></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ffd8a5c3-7cd4-45a7-8261-a97d0aab38e2.jpg">,<p>Courtesy of the artist_<strong>Silence, 2017&nbsp;</strong></p>]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/highlights-of-the-2017-18-mdina-cathedral-art-biennale/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d7d4c141-7f6f-43b8-a800-f185c6e417ff</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 17:48:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nudes in the Forest]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nudes in the Forest</h1>,<p>Elijah Burgher vernisaj at Ivan Gallery in Bucharest</p>,<p>By Eugen Berlo</p>,<p>I had the pleasure of meeting and discussing with Elijah at his first show in Bucharest at <a href="http://www.ivangallery.com/en/exhibition/47/nudes-in-the-forest" title="">IvanGallery</a> the other day. Born in 1978, Kingston, NY, USA, he is an American artist in residency at <a href="http://hortongallery.com/residency/" title="">Horton Gallery studio</a> in Berlin, Germany.  Burgher works with the language of mag­ic and the mystical seals and symbols to address sex­u­al­i­ty, the nude subject and its capacity to convey meaning. Most of his presented artworks are luscious prints on paper realized with handmade heavyweight paper stencils and printmaking techniques. </p>,<p><em>“Titles are important, they’re like breadcrumb trails. The nude is an age-old subject of art. Most crucially for me, the nude has frequently served as a vehicle for expressing love, desire, and beauty, as well as erotic frenzy, terror and pain. The sigils represent desire too, and, like an aroused or arousing nude, they appear in the red alphabet blushing, hot and bothered, full-frontal or spread-eagle, totally naked. I am hoping that the title will be reminiscent of the well-known Baudelaire poem, “Correspondences”, which features the phrase, “forêts de symboles,” usually translated into english as “symbol forest” or “forest of symbols,” but also “cabalistic wood.” I enjoy contemplating being lost in a forest of symbols, of going for a walk in Grunewald, for instance, and seeing the tree branches spell out strange signs, or, alternatively, experiencing Kottbusser Tor, so full of blinking signage, as a wilderness, a place in which to lose oneself. Chants, of course, are simple, repetitive songs or intonations used in ritual. I enjoy the implication that the Chants are the voices of the Nudes, or that there are chanting voices in the forest.“ (Elijah Burgher)</em></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/9fa66920-1c46-49f0-84db-fa68080cc264.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/333d3f12-e153-457c-9cb6-cce3e0f9262c.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/4f1b7358-33ee-4ce7-9b69-46d5049252cc.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/4bfef27e-30f5-4c4a-b49a-801588df8dae.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/8bc3e47c-0ab2-4acb-b031-49a1b6d6ca75.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f2dc41b1-c0e0-4443-a995-2ac93cb58b83.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/c2c2ecf8-a355-4379-8b80-f0f6a458d5a8.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/71bedb07-8788-4c2b-8420-53754edcfb6e.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/210f3361-ac1f-4090-a2dc-da93d29f0ce4.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/c188476b-24a0-440c-b294-cf44e5383daa.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/nudes-in-the-forest/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4b09bfac-7e20-4ee6-a40b-05f464a3fa03</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 13:44:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['SEEING OURSELVES SENSING' by Eastwards Prospectus]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'SEEING OURSELVES SENSING' by Eastwards Prospectus</h1>,<p>by Eugen Berlo 2017-07-15</p>,<p>Tomorrow is the last day, but it’s worth to make an appointment and pay a visit to the gallery. The group show is also a statement by Raluca Soaita and Andrei Breahna. As I like to follow up with a few galleries, I have (Yahveh) to say go and see it!; it is a good one and it will please you to see a nice range of artists, from Razvan Anton, Pavel Braila, Radu Cioca, to Tania Mouraud, Karolina Bregula and Mircea Stanescu. Many thanks to Răzvan Băbiceanu who walked me through.</p>,<p>“This public showing is the way Raluca Soaita and Andrei Breahna responsibly position themselves as related to the artists hosted by their gallery. The constant presence of video in the public space, the American-school photo, the drawing, the installation, the performance, the animation – they all have shaped a certain artist / intellectual profile in the gallery space, one bearing various practices, which EASTWARDS PROSPECTUS is supporting and developing. The exhibition is a coherent and clear discourse about the gallerist/artist relationship, about the exhibition space and the challenges raised by certain works that one feels connected to.” - <a href="https://www.eastwardsprospectus.com/seeing-ourselves-sensing/" title="">read more</a></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/3510b18d-1e6a-48ec-8f4c-12f2ee6a07cb.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/e6aeb1dc-063d-4eb7-a234-b305279ddce3.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/aeba9f7c122a122ec25a472d791f6df13cd796c2.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/9f1ba5716af1f75bbf2ae5a6f03e81bc8edf0a7c.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/fc4a1fc35947c2e2156c983e016e9688f926eefb.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/acb7798c-88e6-4868-92eb-db6122dc9b4b.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f6994efd-b6c7-4183-83e3-07bbe2feb42a.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/bf16a9ef308175a715d956ce43cbabd9017c6a54.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/393b6492d15c9a9d4340d256f2ce5331c28fce66.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/f655a44479baaacc58b018858346076e41989cc1.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/5caa1632-a961-4514-86ca-f4645a4074a2.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/974d1fd1702e89d17a9c42cc7f7726afdfa11109.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/e61fc732-5a40-48c6-8508-59d7936a150f.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/7d5d821221041d2104a4f863120a7680147f11d5.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/seeing-ourselves-sensing-by-eastwards-prospectus/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4ee999b2-4b55-4ff5-83b8-78ee994a6497</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 15:30:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some People Can See Sound, or Taste Color. Does It Make Them More Creative?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Some People Can See Sound, or Taste Color. Does It Make Them More Creative?</h1><p>And what effect does synesthesia have on creativity? Marks explains that creative cognition (essentially an aspect of creativity)-a test of which might ask its subject to conjure as many non-traditional uses for an object like an umbrella as possible-&quot;seems to produce higher scores among populations with synesthesia.&quot;</p><img src="https://artsy-media-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wSAR6TNL2JEpm1WF_eIB9A%2Fcustom-Custom_Size___cody-davis-253928+2.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.artsy.net/article/artsy-editorial-people-sound-taste-color-creative?utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=11995862-newsletter-editorial-daily-01-23-18&amp;utm_campaign=editorial&amp;utm_content=st-S</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">323dcc82-bdb8-4129-8253-bdc83c095a25</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 14:34:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Four Tribes of Art Collectors]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The Four Tribes of Art Collectors</h1><p>This is the tribe most tethered to the dynamism, quarrels, gossip, lawsuits, information, misinformation, fads, and rumors of the contemporary art market. Unlike the connoisseur or trophy-hunter (discussed below), enterprise collectors are wide open to the new and experimental.</p><img src="https://artsy-media-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/zX3uBSiS9lqGNZVBI8ZowQ%2FFour+tribes+thumb+2.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.artsy.net/article/evan-beard-four-tribes-art-collectors?utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=11995862-newsletter-editorial-daily-01-23-18&amp;utm_campaign=editorial&amp;utm_content=st-S</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4a23eab0-8c51-4de8-be99-6176f40ee5db</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 14:34:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leonard Freed: Six Stories]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Leonard Freed: Six Stories</h1>,<p>Steven Kasher Gallery_Leonard Freed: Six Stories / <a href="http://arstler.com/renay-elle-morris/" title="">Renay Elle Morris</a>_ September 2017</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ef2ce1ab-a72f-4e2f-9fef-a82b6b6a48e8.jpg">,<p><em>Hassidics of Brooklyn, 1954</em><br><em>Harlem, 1963</em><br><em>Black in White America, 1963-65</em><br><em>Israel, 1962 and 1967</em><br><em>Italy, 1956-58</em><br><em>Germany, 1961-66</em></p>,<p>As fellow Magnum photographer Cornell Capa expressed in <em>The Concerned Photographer</em>, “… he (<a href="http://mastersofphotography.blogspot.com/2014/08/leonard-freed.html" title="">Leonard Freed</a>) was a photographer of ordinary people going about their every day lives – at home, at work, and in the streets. He has a keen eye for social hierarchies and, in part because of his working class origins; he felt great solidarity with outsiders, and the oppressed.”</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/leonard-freed-six-stories/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3c76c61b-a7f9-449b-9775-42b582944902</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 21:21:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[E-VAPORATUS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>E-VAPORATUS</h1>,<blockquote>Volumetrie permisiv&abreve; Marian Gheorghe invitat C&abreve;lin Vasilescu sculptur&abreve; - Constantin Hostiuc critic

15.2.2017 - 13.3.2017 - Galeria Orizont - Uniunea Arti&#x219;tilor Plastici - Filiala Arte Decorative</blockquote>,<p>I was there for the opening of the show. The gallery is reminiscent of the old communist era, and the show is in plain sight, as one can watch through the windows of the gallery, and even though you have to enter strangely to the back door, once you are inside you get to warm up in the presence of the artworks. You start to recognize the spirit of subtle latin humor in Marian’s approach to his creation of E-Vapotarus, meaning repurposing of sensually tactile vintage objects and cleverly giving them a new life as intricate part of the new objects on display. On the other side against the wall you find yourself immersed into a grave deep lyric emotion of the “Wheels and Chakras” To me they are the definition of solid yet delicate, rustic yet pleasant, technically improbable yet archetypal.</p>,<p>by Genu Berlo</p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/872a343723797adac76b56ac7a1d7d45160da100.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/49ce6da8-7e68-4cfe-8f50-fe251a976d5a.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/677d2401-7dfe-41a8-8993-8d2d25f42b91.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/ec8e96156d7fd17ffc65fe3fea6abb106488fca7.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/4f2ac74950ce27215700f050dc2db6ce4baaacb0.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/1be7078b-f292-4351-bbf1-b247818f3d4d.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/de0b50a6f82257ed59a5c2106499325c140d67b1.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/f4ddbb8dca3220790d7426fde0c9bfde74a4d6eb.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/aba9ae89-3993-4013-ab71-75ac57a20587.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/41d838483f33d24aae200d7e066806fd9431f48d.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/823d7c4e1ed6874a5e114b40322fece028f435f9.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/4ab7f62dade822086653dffbd2c691054342d7b0.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2ef35d5a-ad26-4fa4-8b81-595de3f29992.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/a8752fa1-6776-4bde-982e-991fcbb84b12.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/6fcf677d972001b742c174eb4a291a013715b5dd.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/e206e4a7a59cd662718bcf1e9858101a58262a2e.jpg">,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/291d82b05c6c1e6126584cd5642e31b85c1a5c9b.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/16e003f6-5fda-418b-99fe-9cc6a3fda66e.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/889192ea-ddd7-45d4-80bb-143f3668eb9f.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/afb9f49d-ce42-4949-8a05-52e187a86684.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/7ec1b9d4-3d07-45dc-ab2c-72c0196c05c8.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/e-vaporatus/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a7bdf26a-3865-42bd-b7c1-0e86cf63b007</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 21:09:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[THE CHERKASHIN’S. NEW DRAWINGS. A NEW CHAPTER.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>THE CHERKASHIN’S. NEW DRAWINGS. A NEW CHAPTER.</h1>,<p>Renay Elle Morris / June 2017</p>,<p><strong>For decades, Valera and Natasha Cherkashin</strong> have added layer upon layer of philosophical and political ideology to their masterful works of photographic genius. With exhibitions, lectures and talks on an international stage, the art of their images have recently been compiled into a 254 page publication entitled, <strong>Actions, Happenings and art performances 1962 – 2016 _ Night with a Pioneer Leader</strong>, which delves into a history of 2 artists_a husband and wife team, and the legacy of their talent. What inspires them may not offer an easy answer. Perhaps it is a fearless energy to defend beliefs, or a lifetime of a Soviet regime. Perhaps it was Perestroika, the political movement and the "openness"policy that led to the reforms of the Soviet political and economic system during the1980s that allowed for such ambitious work.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/3df39e8c-e4a5-44a7-bc81-6191dc9c8271.jpg" title="&quot;Untitled 1&quot;">]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/the-cherkashins-new-drawings-a-new-chapter/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">65e3bb98-0608-4b11-add5-042119a20220</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 15:30:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[_lee friedlander at work / a slice of americana in bologna]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>_lee friedlander at work / a slice of americana in bologna</h1>,<p>/ Fondazione Del Monte – Palazzo Paltroni / Bologna Italy  </p>,<p>by Renay Elle Morris / January 2018</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/4bde87b9-d7e4-49b2-bd6b-c95b560650cc.png">,<p>Looking back on 2017, I was fortunate to engage in several photographic presentations that offered specific themes, albeit quite different. In particular, with an invitation to participate in the prestigious 2017-18 Mdina Cathedral Art Biennale in Malta’s <em>The Mediterranean: A Sea of Conflicting Spiritualities</em>, as an exhibiting photographer and the only American to receive this honor, I navigated with both intention, and agenda working in tandem to add Bologna Italy to my itinerary. I boarded planes, trains, buses and such for the 3rd edition of Foto/Industria in association with MAST Fondazione’s BIENNIAL OF PHOTOGRAPHY ON INDUSTRY AND WORK. It was for me, a tasting _a mixture of art and cuisine, as Bologna is Italy’s capital of food. And, I wasn’t disappointed on both counts.</p>,<p>The Biennial (12 October-19 November) highlighted the work of 14 extraordinary image-makers at exhibitions located in galleries throughout a city shrouded by architecture of medieval beginnings. My arrival on 17 November afforded me an opportunity for a quick viewing. Having this very short window, I decided to limit my coverage to the images of Lee Friedlander. The Palazzo Paltroni, was the designated space to host his presentation of <em>At Work</em>.</p>,<p>For introductory purposes, one learns Friedlander is considered one of the foremost photographers of the twentieth and twenty-first centuries. American born (Aberdeen Washington (1934), his images detail America’s social landscape. They have been noted as “keen depictions” that include the worlds of jazz, television, urban landscapes and deserts. <em>At Work</em>, is a monograph dedicated to the urban life of largely the anonymous worker photographed over a 16 year period beginning in 1979. It is a commissioned work offering a cultural fabric woven with images of factories and offices, as well as tools, work practices, and relationships in professional settings. Shot in black and white with the use of a 35mm Leica, the work defined an era. “Friedlander has acknowledged the largely anonymous worker, making inventive pictures of the familiar, humdrum, yet overriding role of work in America.” Throughout the course of this assignment, Friedlander maintained his personal artistic freedom and integrity. True to his aesthetic, it is an outstanding selection of photographs that give homage to a place and time_ a brilliant documentation and archive of Middle America and its working class and social structure.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/119bdf9f-518c-4ce8-8568-2deda43796ae.png">,<p><em><strong>“Friedlander has acknowledged the largely anonymous worker, making inventive pictures of the familiar, humdrum, yet overriding role of work in America.”</strong></em>_ Fraenkel Gallery</p>,<p>What was of great fascination was the play between the view and the viewer. I buried myself between young students engaged in dialogue with professors, individuals from foreign lands, like me _ just enough to catch a few remarks in English and Italian. At various moments, noting the crowds, I thought of how different this all must seem _a retrospective of working class Americans in past decades, in black and white, before digital, before selfies. It was profound.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/8372215e-408f-45fa-b77a-b6507ce0867f.png">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/5e5d513a-e970-475c-8de0-29ecb579ff6a.png">,<p>As a student, I was fortunate to have the experience to work only in black and white, capturing images with the use of 4×5, 2¼ and 35mm cameras_ bracketing exposures. And not to forget, spending countless hours in darkrooms, adjusting enlargers, and submerging hands in developers and fixers. Now, when I stare at Friedlander’s work, I am reminded of how artfully we were trained. How precise we were with every shot. Kudos for MAST and Foto/Industria for its presentation of <em>At Work</em> which ultimately reminds us of this lost art.</p>,<p>Lee Friedlander is represented by Fraenkel Gallery – ­San Francisco, CA. USA</p>,<p>Image: #1 Renay Elle Morris / renayellemorris.com<br>Images: #2, 3, 4 / courtesy of Fraenkel Gallery + Foto/Industria + MAST</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://arstler.com/_lee-friedlander-at-work-a-slice-of-americana-in-bologna/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">acaf28d6-7cb3-4153-ad8d-a1a3a0c306ab</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 17:18:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>